Inventory of the Department of Music Records 1920-2011
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Department of Music Records 1920-[ongoing]
Special Collections Research Center
00/02/01/22/UA 212
3.00
This collection includes fliers, announcements, programs, newsletters, and related material generated by the Department of Music of the College of William and Mary. Topics covered relate to departmental business, visiting performers, recitals and performances by College students and faculty, the Choir and other student vocal and instrumental ensembles, Ewell Concert Series, Jazz Combo, Gallery Players Materials, and other related topics.
Dept. of Music arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Custodial History
Part of this collection was formerly part of the University Archives Publications Collection.
Historical Note
The Department of Music at the College of William and Mary offers programs of study in music composition, theory, performance and musicology. Most of the department's students do not major in music, but rather study music as a life-enriching activity; as such, the program is designed to function as an integral component of the undergraduate curriculum. At the same time, however, the department prepares many of its students for further academic work in the discipline, and in the last ten years has sent graduates off to some of the best musicology, composition, and performance graduate programs in the country.Large ensembles include the William and Mary Symphony Orchestra, the Wind Symphony, the Concert Choir, and the Women's Chorus. Medium-sized ensembles include the Jazz Ensemble, Botetourt Chamber Singers, Appalachian String Band, Middle Eastern Music Ensemble, Early Music Ensemble, Gallery Players, Performance Art Ensemble, and Indonesian Gamelan. In addition, the department regularly offers eight to ten other small ensembles, featuring various combinations of string, percussion, and wind instruments.The department's academic faculty as of 2007 included three composer/theorists, two ethnomusicologists, three music historians, and four conductors. For further current information see http://www.wm.edu/music/. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Dept. of Music.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes fliers, announcements, programs, newsletters, and related material generated by the Department of Music of the College of William and Mary. Topics covered relate to departmental business, visiting performers, recitals and performances by College students and faculty, the Choir and other student vocal and instrumental ensembles, Ewell Concert Series, Jazz Combo, Gallery Players Materials, and other related topics.
Arrangement of Materials
Acc. 2011.325 is currently not fully arranged or described. Consult a staff member for assistance.
Additional Information
Related Materials
Papers of Carl A. "Pappy" Fehr (UA 6.017); Alumni Band Organization (UA 271); William and Mary Pep Band (UA 7.035); University Archives Artifact Collection (UA 13); University Archives Audiovisual Collection (UA 58); University Archives Poster Collection (UA 12); University Archives Photograph Collection (UA 8).
Separated Materials
Photographs of various music ensembles were separated from Acc. 2009.255 on 6/17/2009 and were made part of the University Archives Photograph Collection (UA 8). Three CDs featuring various music ensembles including The New Hellenic Expression, William and Mary Symphony, and a mix CD of various music ensembles were separated from Acc. 2009.255 on 6/17/2009 and were made part of the University Archives Audiovisual Collection (UA 58). Several posters announcing music concerts were separated from Acc. 2009.255 and added to the University Archives Poster Collection (UA 12). The audiovisual material from Acc. 2010.334 was separated from this collection and made part of the University Archives Audiovisual Collection on 6/16/2010. The posters from Acc. 2010.334 were separated from this collection and made part of the University Archives Poster Collection on 6/16/2010. The photographs and audiovisual material were separated from this collection and were made part of the University Archives Photograph Collection and University Archives Audiovisual Collection, respectively, on 5/25/2011.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Choir and Chorus; College Opera; College of William and Mary. Dept. of Music; Concert Band; Orchestra; Williamsburg Friends of Music (Williamsburg, Va.)
Genre/Form of Material:
Announcements; Fliers (printed matter); Posters; Programs; Publications
Topical Term:
College of William and Mary--History--20th century.; College of William and Mary--Students.; Concerts; Music--Instruction and study--United States.; Music--Virginia--Williamsburg.; Newsletters.; Pamphlets; Recitals; Universities and Colleges--Virginia--Faculty
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Publications, 1920-[ongoing]; id112214
  - id27486 (Box 1)
    - Announcements, 1920-1939; id56835 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Announcements, 1939-[ongoing]; id56836 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Baroque Chamber Players, 1983-1986; id56837 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Botetourt Chamber Singers, 1983-[ongoing]; id56838 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Brass Quintet, 1985; id56839 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Capriole, 1991-1994; id56840 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Choir--Certificate of Merit, undated; id56841 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Choir--Concerts, 1933-1957; id56842 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Choir and Chorus Concerts, 1940-1966; id59080 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - id27487 (Box 2)
    - Choir--Concerts, 1958-1986; id56844 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Choir--Fundraisers, 1984-1999; id56849 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Choir--Informational Brochures, 1965-2009; id56850 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Choir--Postcards, undated; id56851 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Choir and Chorus Concerts, Spring 1967-Spring 1974; id56846 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Choir and Chorus Concerts, Christmas 1974-Spring 1984; id56847 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Choir and Chorus Concerts, Christmas 1984-; id56848 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Chorus--Concerts, 1940-[ongoing]; id56845 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Chorus--Postcards, undated; id56852 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Chorus--Womens Chorus, 2006; id56853 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Clayman Concert, id71486 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - id27488 (Box 3)
    - College Opera, 1932-; id56854 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Collegium Musicum Series, 1960-1974; id56856 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Commencement, 2001-2009; id56857 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Concert Band, 1955-1979; id56858 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Concert Band, 1955-1979; id56859 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Concert Band, 1986-2006; id56860 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Course Offerings, 1939-1996; id56861 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Early Music Ensemble, 1994-[ongoing]; id56862 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Events Calendar, 2003-2004; id56863 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Ewell Concert Series, 1991-[ongoing]; id56864 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - id71492 (Box 4)
    - Faculty Concert Series, 1942-1984; id56865 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Gallery Players, undated; id56866 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Gamelan, 2002-[ongoing]; id56867 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Gospel Festival, 2005-2007; id56868 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Guitar Ensemble, 1986; id56869 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - History of The Department of Music, 1904-1980, circa 1980; id56871 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Jazz Ensemble, 1990-[ongoing]; id56872 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Marching Band, 1979-1980; id56873 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Masterclasses, 2004-2007; id56874 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Middle Eastern Music Ensemble, 1995-[ongoing]; id56875 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Miscellaneous Events, 2003-2009; id56877 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Music In America Culture Series, 1999-2007; id56876 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - id27489 (Box 5)
    - Opera Workshop, 2006; id56878 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Orchestra, 1939-1983; id56879 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Orchestra, 1984-1999; id56880 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Orchestra, 2000-[ongoing]; id56870 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Recitals, Faculty, 1939-1995; id59149 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - id27537 (Box 6)
    - Recitals--Student, 1934-1979; id27538 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Recitals--Student, 1980-1984; id27539 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Recitals--Student, 1980-1984; id59209 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Recitals--Student, 1985-1990; id59210 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Recitals--Student, 1991-2000; id59211 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Recitals--Student, 2001-[ongoing]; id59212 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Schedules, 1963-2001; id59213 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Scholarship Award Recipients, 2003-2009; id59214 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - The Semi-Quaver, 1980-1982; id59215 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - id59218 (Box 7)
    - Student Activities--Choir Trip to Europe, 1987; id59219 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Student Activities--Choir Trip to Europe, 1984; id59220 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Tercentenary Music Festival, 1993; id59221 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - The Williamsburg Friends of Music, 1963-1970; id59222 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Wind Symphony, 2000-[ongoing]; id59223 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Acc. 2011.325: Posters, Fliers, Programs, etc., 1994-2011; id112216